In this lecture, I am going to give you a high level overview of Amazon Bedrock Knowledge
Basins which is the core capability part of Amazon Bedrock where you can build a rack-based
application.
So, over this section, we are going to deep dive into each aspect of Amazon Bedrock
Knowledge Basins but for now, I will just give you a high level overview to get started.
So what is Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Basins? It is a fully managed rack capability in Amazon
Bedrock.
So what it means is AWS will take care of the hosting monitoring, scaling, patching and so on
for this particular service.
So, Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Basins gives foundation models and agents contextual information
from companies' private data sources to deliver more relevant, accurate and customized responses.
So, we already discussed earlier that RAG allows you to connect with your company's private
data sources so that is what Bedrock Knowledge Basins does.
But the good thing is AWS takes care of all the complexity related to building the
RAG-based application, all you have to do is select the configuration from the options
provided by Bedrock Knowledge Basins and then you should be easily able to build the RAG-based
application.
Now, previously, we looked at the 10 different architectural decisions that you need
to make to build a RAG-based application.
And in Bedrock Knowledge Basins, all those capabilities are available out of box.
So, first, you can select your data source, it provides option for both structured and
unstructured data, then you can select your chunking strategy, so there are different chunking
strategies available in Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Basins, then you can select your embedding
model, again, there are a lot of choices from Amazon, Cohear and so on, then you can select
your vector database, there are a lot of different choices that are available based on
your use case, you can choose a re-ranker model and then finally, you can also select
the foundation model from Amazon Bedrock that might be relevant for your use case.
So, you can select the different options and then your RAG application should be ready.
So, we are going to deep dive into all of these 10 decision points as we go along in
the course, so if it is not clear to you, that should be okay.
So, this is very important and you should remember from the Amazon Bedrock Knowledge Basins
perspective, there are two APIs available, the retrieve API and retrieve and generate API,
so what retrieve API does is, it is a retrieval only, so it will perform vector search return
retrieved chunks, so there is no LLM response generation and it is used when you want to search
results only, so basically it targets from step 1 to step 4, so let us say if you invoke
the retrieve API and you send this question, how many leaves in 2026, it is only going
to respond with retrieved chunks, it is not going to give you a final answer.
Then you have the retrieve and generate API, it retrieves relevant chunks and sends
them to the foundation model to generate final answer, so this is full-write, so this
covers from step 1 to step 5, so if you send let us say this as a prompt and invoke
the retrieve and generate API, you will get a full-fledged answer, so you need to remember
this from the exam perspective, okay, so that is pretty much it from this lecture, I will
see in the next lecture, thank you.